<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-cherry-blossom-trees</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1909-10-19/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WASHINGTON, Oct. 18.-
When the honorary commercial commissioners 
of Japan arrive in Washington, November 1, they will be taken on an automobile ride which will include Potomac drive, 
along which 2000 cherry trees to be presented to this country by the emperor of Japan are to be planted.
The shipment of the trees and the planting thereof have been entrusted to Torakiro Watase, Tokio plant company, 
who is one of the commissioners. Speaking of the gift of the emperor to the city of Washington, Mr. Watase
said the trees would be sent to Mrs. Taft, wife of the president, and presented by her to the government 
for transplanting along Potomac drive. Former President Roosevelt and President Taft are chiefly 
responsible for the improvement of the Potomac river front, and it was Mrs. Taft who gave the name Potomac park 
to that section of the city. She made popular the afternoon promenades on the drive, which were a feature last year of 
summer life in the capital. New York Remembered The emperor of Japan is sending to New York also a large number 
of cherry trees to be planted along Riverside drive and Grant's tomb. In Japan, the land of the blossom, there are many 
beautiful legends about the trees and the flower of the cherry. The blossom of the Japanese cherry is of a peculiarly delicate 
beauty, and there is a tradition in Japan that if that same tone appears in the blossoms of the Japanese cherry planted 
in another country, that country can be taken and subjugated by Japan.
Mr. Watase is authority for the statement that while many Japanese cherry trees have been brought to the United States, 
the color of the blossoms, although just as beautiful, is unlike the blossom which appears in Japan."Therefore," 
he said, "we conclude that we could not take America, even if we wanted to."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016187/1909-12-23/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
