<topics>
  <topic>
    <id>https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-cherry-blossom-trees</id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85042462/1909-10-19/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>WASHINGTON, Oct. 18.-
When the honorary commercial commissioners 
of Japan arrive in Washington, November 1, they will be taken on an automobile ride which will include Potomac drive, 
along which 2000 cherry trees to be presented to this country by the emperor of Japan are to be planted.
The shipment of the trees and the planting thereof have been entrusted to Torakiro Watase, Tokio plant company, 
who is one of the commissioners. Speaking of the gift of the emperor to the city of Washington, Mr. Watase
said the trees would be sent to Mrs. Taft, wife of the president, and presented by her to the government 
for transplanting along Potomac drive. Former President Roosevelt and President Taft are chiefly 
responsible for the improvement of the Potomac river front, and it was Mrs. Taft who gave the name Potomac park 
to that section of the city. She made popular the afternoon promenades on the drive, which were a feature last year of 
summer life in the capital. New York Remembered The emperor of Japan is sending to New York also a large number 
of cherry trees to be planted along Riverside drive and Grant's tomb. In Japan, the land of the blossom, there are many 
beautiful legends about the trees and the flower of the cherry. The blossom of the Japanese cherry is of a peculiarly delicate 
beauty, and there is a tradition in Japan that if that same tone appears in the blossoms of the Japanese cherry planted 
in another country, that country can be taken and subjugated by Japan.
Mr. Watase is authority for the statement that while many Japanese cherry trees have been brought to the United States, 
the color of the blossoms, although just as beautiful, is unlike the blossom which appears in Japan."Therefore," 
he said, "we conclude that we could not take America, even if we wanted to."</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016187/1909-12-23/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Our new Potomac Park, down beyond the monument, 
is to be beautified by Japanese cherry trees. Col. Cosby, Superintendent of Public Buildings and Grounds,
has been informed by Jukio Ozaki, the Mayor of Tokyo, Japan, that the 2,000 cherry trees which were presented to the city of Washington,
have arrived at Seattle, and will be shipped at once to this city. The Mayor of Tokyo said in his letter: "It gives me great
pleasure to inform you that the corporation of Tokyo,at a recent meeting of its Councils, resolved to present 2,000 Japanese
cherry trees to the Government of the United States for the use of the city of Washington." And the Mayor goes on to say:"The cherry
trees are extensively cultivated in this country, and are the most admired of the flowering trees. Ten of the most 
representative kinds have been selected, and I beg to assure you that it will remain to the citizens of Tokyo a pleasing memory, 
as well as a matter of civic pride, to know that their small offering will be permitted to contribute to the advancement 
of the beautiful Capital of the admire great Republic which they all admire</text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86069675/1910-01-19/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	<rel>1</rel>
	<text>Japanese Cherry Trees Presented to Mrs. Taft 
The Emperor of Japan's remembrance of President Taft's great enjoyment of the cherry blossom festival season when 
in Japan has taken the graceful form of the presentation to Mrs. Taft of three carloads of young cherry trees, 
and they are now in Washington. The greatest care has been taken all the way from the land of the Mikado to keep the
temperature at an even stage so that the trees may not be harmed. Mrs. Taft, in appreciation of the opportunity for a 
cherry blossom season at the National Capital, has instructed the delivery of the trees to the District Commissioners, 
and rows of them lining Pennsylvania Boulevard will be a beautiful feature of that imposing thoroughfare.</text>
	</result>
	<result>
	  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86069675/1910-01-19/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
	  <rel>1</rel>
	  <text>Gifts from Tokyo to Washington Found To Be Badly Diseased
Washington, Jan. 28—Regret has been expressed by the President and by Mrs. Taft because two thousand Japanese cherry trees, 
presented by the municipality of Tokyo to this government for use in the national capital, have been found to be infected with
root gall worms, certain diseases, and insect pests, some of which were hitherto unknown in this country.
The trees were to have been planted in Potomac Park, which Mrs. Taft worked hard last year to make into an outdoor boulevard and 
meeting place for social Washington. The Secretary of Agriculture found it necessary to recommend the destruction of the trees. 
Secretary Knox has expressed to the Japanese Ambassador the regret of the government authorities that the gift cannot be used. 
Colonel Cosby, in charge of Public Buildings and Grounds, has conveyed the government's regrets to the Mayor of Tokyo.</text>
	</result>
	<result>
	  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1910-10-16/ed-1/seq-1/</id>
	  <rel>0</rel>
	</result>
	<result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82016187/1910-12-22/ed-1/seq-5/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
	<text> It will be remembered that the Emperor of Japan last Spring sent several thousand Japanese cherry trees to Mrs.Taft 
to be placed along the Potomac Drive, which she originated. These cherry trees were found to be infected with a peculiar 
injurious Japanese insect, and for fear they would contaminate the cherry trees in this country the whole lot was burned.
It is now announced that the Japanese authorities are sending another consignment of cherry trees that have been examined and 
shown to be clear of all disease. </text>
	</result>
	<result>
	  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030214/1912-03-06/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	  <rel>1</rel>
	  <text>CHERRY TREES ON THE WAY 
Long Delayed Japanese Gift to City Soon to Arrive
The long-awaited cherry trees, which the Japanese government offered to present to this city at the time of the Hudson-Fulton celebration,
will be here in a few days. The consignment, which includes 2,100 young cherry trees, arrived last week in Seattle and is now being shipped 
to this city over the Great Northern Railroad. Park Commissioner Stover said yesterday that he had written to the Department of Agriculture 
in Washington to send a man here to examine the trees to make sure that no ruinous tree disease was being imported at the same time.
In explaining the delay of the trees, the Park Commissioner said the first trees prepared for shipment were found to have a blight.
"Then the Japanese authorities promised to have these trees reach here just about this time," said the Commissioner, "which shows the 
calculating powers of the Japanese."The problem of where to plant such a number of trees is bothering the Commissioner. Charles D. Lay, 
the landscape architect, has been asked to prepare plans at once, because it will be necessary to plant the trees as soon as the weather is favorable.
The Japanese, interested in the placement of the trees, want many of them planted around Grant's Tomb. Last winter, a bronze tablet,
on which was engraved a scene of Grant's Tomb surrounded by the cherry trees, was presented by Japanese citizens, 
and it is taken as indicating where at least some of them must go to meet the expectations of the donors. </text>
	</result>
	<result>
	  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045433/1912-03-28/ed-1/seq-12/</id>
	  <rel>0</rel>
	</result>
	<result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1913-04-06/ed-1/seq-10/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
	<text> Mikado's Gift to United States Forms Avenue of Delicate Beauty 
Blossoms Signal the Passage of Time
In all the riot of blossoms that have burst forth in Potomac Park within the last week, making that tract the most gorgeous anywhere 
in the District, there is none that shows more delicate beauty than the blooms on the Japanese cherry trees, which were presented to 
the United States by the government of Japan a year ago. These fragrant, beautiful trees are blooming this year for the first time. 
The river drive, from the Virginia bridge up to Twenty-sixth Street, is fragrant with them, and thousands have stopped their carriages 
to admire the delicacy and beauty of the blooms. Unlike other cherry varieties, the Japanese variety leans more towards blooming than 
fruit-bearing. The chief strength of the trees seems to be spent in putting forth the wonderful clusters of blossoms which cover the limbs. 
The trees have been planted for just a little more than a year and, of course, have not yet obtained any beauty in terms of symmetry. 
The pruning knife has not yet had the opportunity to work toward symmetry, and the branches spread awkwardly beside the main stem.
Blossoms Are Beautiful The blossoms, however, are as beautiful now as they will be in years to come and make the observer forget the 
shape of the tree. In appearance, the blooms are a delicate pink, shading almost to white in some instances. Each cluster is made up of dozens 
of individual blossoms, which are formed somewhat like the wild rose. A little over a year ago, the Department of Agriculture received a 
consignment of several hundred cherry trees from Japan. One of the shipments was found to be infected with scale disease, and, for fear that 
a new tree plague might spread from the District, the heads of the department considered destroying the whole lot of several hundred trees. 
Closer inspection disclosed that the trees affected were in the minority, and, after removing the affected ones, the remainder were planted.
The original intention was to plant the cherry trees all over the District of Columbia. However, after the scale was discovered, 
the plan was changed, and the trees were planted along the riverbank in Potomac Park. In this location, they are practically segregated, 
and, if the scale develops further, it will be a relatively simple matter to keep the disease in a restricted area until it is eradicated.</text>
	</result>
	<result>
	  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn84026749/1919-04-07/ed-1/seq-3/</id>
	  <rel>1</rel>
	  <text>GLIMPSE OF NIPPON NEAR TIDAL BASIN 
Japan has come to the United States—just a little slice of the Flowery Kingdom, to be sure—but enough to make even the most unimaginative 
person long to see cherry blossom time in Nippon.Down at the Tidal Basin, on the other side of the Monument, a display of Japanese cherry trees 
is in full and fragrant bloom—blooms that are trying to merge with all their delicate pinkness and sweetness to announce that spring is here, 
that they live but to weave garlands for her costumes and wreaths for her hair. Yesterday, every member of the Japanese embassy made a pilgrimage 
to the cherry trees from their far-away country. They stood in wonder and delight at the sight of the flowers they love so well. It was like being 
transported back to Japan—for a few happy moments, they said. But it’s only a glimpse of what Japan really looks like, they declared, for in their country, 
the trees are less than a bit smaller than our trees, although not a whit less lovely. The climate here is good for the fall blooming of the Japanese trees.
The cherry trees came straight from Japan several years ago and found a home in this country. What could be more appropriate for a dwelling place 
than the National Capital, and what more delightful and easily accessible location than around the Tidal Basin? So they were planted, 
took deep root and life, and every spring will display more profuse and lovely charms. It was the city of Tokyo, through the mayor, 
that made it possible for Washingtonians to have a glimpse of Japan as it looks in the soft, beautiful springtime, 
which has been the inspiration of many lovers. Thousands of maidens pledge their troth under the cherry blossoms, 
demonstrating that American boys and girls can hold hands under the same trees that have inspired young couples in faraway Japan.</text>
	</result>
	<result>
	  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1921-03-27/ed-1/seq-61/</id>
	  <rel>0</rel>
	</result>
	<!-- Additional documents search -->
	<result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83045462/1956-06-27/ed-1/seq-64/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
	</result>
	<result>
	  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82015411/1919-11-18/ed-1/seq-2/</id>
	  <rel>0</rel>
	</result>
	<result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83025812/1936-04-17/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
        <rel>1</rel>
	<text> Washington Hasn't The Only Japanese Cherries
As lovely as any Japanese cherry tree that blossoms in Washington, is the opinion of hundreds of people who have ridden out 
West Main Street during the past two weeks to view a Japanese cherry tree in full bloom in the yard of the Howard Kramers.
The tree in question is large and beautifully formed, and the yield of blossoms is luxurious. It came into bloom about two weeks ago.</text>
	</result>
	<result>
	  <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn86091196/1922-07-21/ed-1/seq-10/</id>
	  <rel>0</rel>
	  </result>
	<result>
        <id>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85040437/1922-04-13/ed-1/seq-7/</id>
        <rel>0</rel>
	<text> 


		
	
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
  <topic>
    <id></id>
    <results>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
      <result>
	<id>/</id>
	<rel></rel>
	<text></text>
      </result>
    </results>
  </topic>
</topics>
